Guide to the Chester Naramore Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Chester Naramore papers
1897-1972
SC0544
Naramore, Chester.
Naramore, Chester
4.75 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of William P. Harris, 1998
Information about Access
None.
BIOGRAPHY
Chester Naramore earned his A.B. in geology at Stanford University in 1903. While at Stanford, he was on the varsity track team, Business Manager for the 1903 Stanford Quad, member of the Geology Society, vice-president of the student body during his senior year, and active in Encina Club affairs. He married Grace Ellen Chilson on March 15, 1904. He pursued a career as geologist and company executive with several oil and gas companies.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The papers of Chester Naramore include correspondence, financial and legal documents, notebooks, and journals, largely pertaining to his business interests, with some items from his college years at Stanford.
Access Terms
Abendroth, Otto; Harbers, Camilla.; Naramore, Grace Chilson.; North European Oil Co..; Oppenheimer, Fritz E.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Students.;; Sunburst Madison Oil Corporation..; Journals.; Petroleum industry and trade--Germany.; Petroleum industry and trade--United States.
Collection Contents
- Business Records, Series 1
  - Abendroth, Kurt, correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abendroth, Kurt, correspondence with DeWilda Harris, 1971-72 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abendroth, Otto, correspondence, 1947-49 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abendroth, Otto, correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abendroth, Otto, correspondence, 1951-53 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Abendroth, Otto, correspondence, 1954-56 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abendroth, Otto, correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Abendroth, Otto, correspondence, 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alaska coal interests, correspondence, 1955-56 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alaska Petroleum, correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alaska Petroleum, correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alaska Petroleum, correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alaska Petroleum, correspondence and documents, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Beyer, Arthur, correspondence, 1959-60 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Mr. Chilson (father-in-law), 1920-43 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1920-56 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - EMEX, agreements, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - EMEX, correspondence, 1953-55 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Harbers, Camilla, correspondence, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Oppenheimer, Fritz, correspondence, 1929-33 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Oppenheimer, Fritz, Pan-Trading & Nord Oil agreements, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - North European Oil Co., correspondence and documents, 1937-54 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - North European Oil Co., correspondence and documents, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - North European Oil Co., correspondence and documents, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - North European Oil Co., correspondence and documents, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - North European Oil Co., correspondence and documents, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - North European Oil Co., correspondence and documents, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - North European Oil Co., correspondence and documents, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Passport of Chester Naramore, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Sunburst Madison Oil Corporation, accounts and correspondence, 1958-59 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sunburst Madison Oil Corporation, memos for files of, 1957-59 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sunburst Madison Oil Corporation, report to stockholders for, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Veach, A. C., correspondence, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Student Papers, Series 2
  - Chilson, Grace - high school notebook, history, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Student notebook (S.U.) - analytic geometry and French, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Student notebook (S.U.) - calculus, mechanics (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Student notebook (S.U.) - chemistry, 1901-02 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Student notebook (S.U.) - record of letters, accounts, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Loose items from: Student notebook (S.U.) - record of letters, accounts, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Journals, Series 3
  - Miscellaneous notes, including Europe, 1917-18 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Europe, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Europe, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - China, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Siberia, 1921-23 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Journal (with entries for added), 1923 1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Angola trip, 1924 May-Aug (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Angola trip, 1924 Oct-1926 Jan (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Two loose items from: Angola 1924-26 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Germany, 1929 Jan-Sep (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Loose items from: Germany 1929 Jan. - Sept. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Germany, 1929-30 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - NEO: Germany, 1929-30 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - German oil fields, 1930-31 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1931-32 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Loose items from: Journal 1936 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Journal Trips, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1952 Jan 16-Dec 31; 1946 Jan 1-15 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)